

Kate Hinrichs

Software Developer

ko.hinrichs@gmail.com | 763.772.4512



/kohinrichs



in /in/kate-hinrichs



kohinrichs.github.io

After frustrating experiences implementing new software, I applied to Nashville Software School. Motivated to find efficient and effective solutions, I wanted to learn how to build software so I could help businesses - both big and small - create the tools they need to address their unique challenges.

Technical Skills

- Git & GitHub version control
- Creating ERDs and wireframe designs
- Developing applications using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, C#, .Net, MS SQL

Projects

MOBI

An app that lets users create custom interval training workouts. Users add moves to their exercise library and use those moves to build workouts. Favorite workouts can be saved and used again and again.

JavaScript, React, CSS, and JSON Server

Holidough

A full stack app bakeries can use to take and manage orders for events and holidays. Includes customer portal and admin management

JavaScript, React, Reactstrap, C#, and .Net

Education

Iowa State University

Bachelor of Science | Cum Laude Apparel Merchandising & Design Concentration - Product Development

Technical Experience

Nashville Software School | May 2021

A six month, full-time program with a focus on project based learning and emphasis on not only skills but thinking like a software developer.

Experience

Dozen Bakery | Operations + Project Manager April 2018 - June 2020 | 37203

- Designed systems for ingredient and supply ordering and price tracking
- Led implementation of new wholesale management software
- Wrote documentation for new systems and roles at the bakery
- Researched and implemented changes in sourcing that lead to a 7% decrease in overall COGS in a year with a 10% increase in gross revenue

2015 - 2019

Nestle Toll House | Lead Baker | 60607

 Acted as a brand ambassador for an international company while navigating multiple agency relationships and stakeholder interests

The Peach Truck | Farm to Porch Director | 37208

• Led the FTP team through a season of unprecedented growth (Shipped more boxes of peaches in the first week of the season than had been shipped in the entire previous 13 week season in total.)

Flavor Catering & Special Occasions | Hospitality Liaison + Event Kitchen Lead | 37203

• Consistently guided teams of 3 - 12 kitchen staff through event service of high quality meals for 20 - 600 guests

Nisolo | Project Manager July 2012 - June 2014 | 37208

· Gained valuable experience working at a fashion startup during the early growth stages